<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Garbage Collection</title>
    <link>https://vodden.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Garbage Collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vodden.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Writing a Geometric Solver in Python - Part 1: Modelling Constraints</title>
      <link>https://vodden.com/posts/constraining-the-point/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vodden.com/posts/constraining-the-point/</guid>
      <description>PySketcher is little library which I maintain which makes it simple (hopefully) to draw geometric images. It was originally written by Hans Petter Langtangen, who sadly passed away in 2016, and since 2019 I&amp;rsquo;ve been keeping it up to date and adding features.
Right now, PySketcher only supports absolute positioning of shapes. This means that you have to know exactly where you&amp;rsquo;d like the center of your circle to be and exactly what radius it should have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MathJax and Hugo</title>
      <link>https://vodden.com/posts/mathjax-and-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vodden.com/posts/mathjax-and-hugo/</guid>
      <description>The is a marvelous article which explains how to use Hugo and MathJax in close harmony. Unfortunately it was written a while ago and only works for MathJax 2.x. This article updates the content of the original to MathJax &amp;gt; 3.1. The original is still worth reading as it nicely explains the functionality.
Firstly MathJax &amp;gt; 3.0 likes to have pollyfill. So the script inclusion should look like this:
1 2  &amp;lt;script src=&amp;#34;https://polyfill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Git ready to rumble</title>
      <link>https://vodden.com/posts/lets-git-ready-to-rumble/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vodden.com/posts/lets-git-ready-to-rumble/</guid>
      <description>Solving it If found myself with a rather strange git problem. As far as I was aware, I was tracking a remote, however when ever I git a git pull, my bash prompt would show me as having commits outstanding.
[voddenr:~/repository] master(4)+i ± Looking at the commit tree, it would seem that origin/HEAD and origin/master have not been correctly updated:
* f786359 - (HEAD -&amp;gt; master) Merge everything together. (3 hours ago) &amp;lt;Richard Vodden&amp;gt; | * 51955ca - Wrote some code.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
